codefetti.com 2019-05-25

# Codefetti LLC Privacy Policy | Codefetti LLC Affordable Small Business Website Design

_Updated 6/14/2018_

### Introduction

Our website address is: [https://codefetti.com](https://codefetti.com/).

At codefetti.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information that is received and collected by codefetti.com and how it is used. This information is collected through cookies including web beacons, web server logs, JavaScript, and other tracking technologies.

Your use of our website indicates that you have read and understand our policy, what cookies are, and how you can manage them.

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to [contact us.](https://codefetti.com/contact-us/ "Contact Us")

#### What are Cookies?

A cookie is a small text file on your computer which identifies your browser and stores certain information.

Codefetti.com does use cookies to store information about visitor preferences. We record user-specific information such as which pages you access or visit.  We may also retain search information that you enter on our site. These cookies are stored for one month.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Codefetti.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

### Information we collect and why we collect it

#### WordPress

Our site is built on the WordPress framework. WordPress uses cookies to verify who you are. There are cookies for logged in users and for commenters.

#### Comments

When visitors leave comments on our site, we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service is provided by Automattic (the makers of WordPress).  After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

[View Automattic’s Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/).

#### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

#### Contact forms

Whenever you submit a comment or contact form through our website, we may ask for your name and email address. Your information is encrypted as it transmits from your browser to our web server so that your private information is not intercepted by third parties. In addition, we never share or sell your information to third parties.

The information you submit  is used solely to respond to website inquiries or comments and is deleted after one month.

#### MailChimp Newsletter

If you previously subscribed to our MailChimp mailing list, at that time you explicitly gave permission for us to email you our periodic newsletters. The information you provided includes your name and email address and your method of sign up.  That information is contained on MailChimp’s servers indefinitely. However, you may unsubscribe from our list or request deletion from the list at any time.

#### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

Codefetti.com has no control over these websites and how they may track or use personal data that they may collect.

#### Log Files

Like many other Web sites, codefetti.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track users movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

This information is provided as analytics and described in further detail below.

### Who we share your data with

We do business with the following third parties. They collect and use your personal information through secure SSL encryption as follows:

  * [Google Analytics](https://policies.google.com/privacy) – Google Analytics uses log files as described above. Google does not have access to this data, but anyone who has access to your search console will have access to this data.
  * [Cloudflare](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacyshield/) – Cloudflare is a content delivery network (CDN) that analyzes traffic to our website in an effort to prevent bad bot attacks.
  * [A2 Hosting](https://www.a2hosting.com/about/policies#Terms-Of-Service) –  Provides and uses web traffic statistics as per log files above in an effort to prevent bad bot attacks and provide anonymous visitor demographic data for our website.
  * [YouTube](https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7671399?hl=en) – We provide embedded tutorials on our website which is treated the same as if watching directly on YouTube. YouTube will use the IP information to record video views.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website as editors or administrators, we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

For visitors that submit a contact form, your information is deleted within a month, providing us with adequate time to respond to your request and/or receive additional communication from you.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

Please fee free to [contact us](https://codefetti.com/contact-us/) with any questions or comments.

By using our website you agree to our Cookie Policy and Privacy Policy.
